# **FETTAH KIRAN**

346 - 201 - 0986 | fkiran@uh.edu | linkedin.com/in/fettahkiran | f-kiran.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

A Ph.D. student conducting research in the Affective & Data Computing [ACDC] lab under the esteemed guidance of Prof. Ioannis Pavlidis. My academic journey includes an M.S. in Computer Science earned at Louisiana State University.

#### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D., Computer Science

Expected Aug 2024

University of Houston, Houston, TX

3.4 GPA

College of Natural Sciences and Mathematics

Relevant coursework: Statistical Methods in Research

Research: Affective Computing, Human-Computer Interaction, Physiological Signal Processing

M.S., Computer Science

May 2020

Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, LA

3.5 GPA

Division of Computer Science and Engineering

B.S., Department of Computer and Instructional Technologies Education

May 2013

Ondokuz Mayis University, Samsun, Turkiye

3.0 GPA

Faculty of Education

Relevant coursework: Material Design, Programming Languages, AI, Distance Learning

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Data Analysis and Statistics: Multimodel Data, R, Python Design and Modeling Tools: Xcode, SwiftUI, Canvas, Draw.io

Relevant coursework: Brain Computer Interaction, ADHD, Serious Games

**Programming:** Python, R, Swift, C++

Operating Systems: MS Windows, MacOS, Bash, Linux

Certifications: LSU IRB - December 2019, Human Research Investigation. CITI - University of Houston

## **EXPERIENCE**

Department of Computer Science, University of Houston, TX: Graduate Teaching Assistant Aug 2021 – Present

- Graded and prepared solutions for assignments, midterms, and finals for graduate-level courses; Statistical Methods in Research (R), Ubiquitous Computing (Swift), Machine Learning (Python), Data Science II (Python)
- Guided 20+ students on 6 University Computer Science labs on data acquisition, processing, and reporting results of experiments.
- Consistently received positive feedback [Fall 2022, Spring 2023, Fall 2023] resulting in a 4.6/5.0 on student evaluations.

Texas Institute for Measurement, Evaluation and Statistics, Houston, TX: Research Assistant Jun 2023 – Aug 2023

- Prepared experimental setup
- Collected, curated, and visualized NSF-funded Affective Math project data using R
- Developed analytic methods in R

## **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

Affective Math Project, University of Houston, TX: Researcher

Fall 2020 - Present

Collaborated in CPL team to conduct a project, Affective Math, funded from NSF (#1760760)

- · Executed experiments
- Collecting and curating data (R)
- · Developed analytic methods

M.S. Degree Study, Louisiana State University, LA: Researcher

Fall 2018 - Spring 2020

- Developed an experimental protocol to explore the effects of background music in a serious game on attention in children with ADHD using Tetris and a brain-computer interface setup
- Conducting experiments with and without ADHD students
- Analyzed and presented the results to committee members

# **PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. Arpaci I., Karatas K., Kiran F., Kusci I., Topcu A. (2021). Mediating role of positivity in the relationship between state anxiety and problematic social media use during the COVID-19 pandemic *Death Studies*. doi.org/10. 1080/07481187.2021.1923588
- Soysal OM., Kiran F., Chen J. (2020). Quantifying Brain Activity State: EEG analysis of Background Music in A Serious Game on Attention of Children 4th International Symposium on Multidisciplinary Studies and Innovative Technologies (ISMSIT). doi.org/10.1109/ISMSIT50672.2020.9255308
- 3. Kiran F. (2020). Exploring effects of background music in a serious game on attention by means of EEG signals in children. *Louisiana State University and Agricultural & Mechanical College*.

## **OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE**

Distance Learning Center, Canakkale Onsekiz Mart University, Turkiye: Content Developer

2013 - 2015

- Designed class materials (PowerPoint)
- · Resolved technical issues in Adobe Connect to ensure the smooth completion of each live session

Department of Education, Ondokuz Mayis University, Turkiye: Teaching Internship

Sep 2012 - May 2013

Assisted primary school students and teachers in computer class sessions with trendy materials and methods

# **SEMINARS AND CONFERENCES**

ACII2023 - Affective Computing Intelligent Interaction, The MIT Media Lab, Cambridge, MA, USA

Sep 10-13, 2023

Position: Participant

8th International Computer Instructional Technology, Trakya University, Edirne, Turkiye

Sep 2014

Position: Participant

## **HONORS AND AWARDS**

YLSY Scholarship, The Ministry of National Education of Turkiye

Aug 2017 - Present

Full-ride scholarship to pursue a M.S. and PhD. education abroad by the Turkish government

LSU Global Game Jam, Louisiana Digital Media Center, Baton Rouge, LA

Jan 2019

The Global Game Jam (GGJ) is the world's largest game jam event (game creation)